一直以来 我都惊叹于 玛莎那不断刷新下限的能力
It always amazed me how Martha managed to surpass herself
她总能想出 各种变态的新花样来折磨我
with new and twisted ways of getting to me.
但把我父母扯进来
But involving my parents,
跟他们说我车祸受伤 实在太过分了
telling them I'd been injured in a car crash, that was next level.
走向那所房子时 我以为门背后等着我的
I expected a lot when I walked up to the house that day.
会是一派兵荒马乱 爸妈也许在哭 而我得费力地解释这一切
A lot of panic. Crying, maybe. A hell of a lot of explaining.
但我没想到的是
What I didn't expect, though,
一进门 却发现我爸正在跟她通话
was finding my dad on the phone to her when I walked in.
我警告过你了 贱人 再给我打电话
I've told you, you bitch, you call me again,
我就去伦敦砍了你的两条腿
I'll come to London and cut your legs off.
对 你听见了 两条腿
Yeah, you heard. Your legs.
哦? 是吗?
You will, will ya?
那我告诉你 没了腿 要想那么干可是难比登天
That's gonna be pretty fucking hard to do with no legs, let me tell you.
她怎么会知道爸的手机号码?
How did she get his mobile?
是公司前台给她的 她谎称是你爸的客户
The receptionist at work gave it to her. Said she was a client.
她昨天一整天 都在到处给你爸的同事打电话
You know she spent yesterday phoning round his colleagues,
说他是恋童癖 她小时候被他猥亵过
calling him a pedo, telling them he fiddled her when she was a child.
天啊
Christ.
你这冒充律师的疯婆子 可真好意思说
Says the fucking mad bitch pretending to be a fucking lawyer!
人事部还为此找他谈话了
HR pulled him up on it too.
- 天哪 他是怎么回应的? - 你爸的脾气你也知道
- Jesus. How did he respond to that? - You know what your dad's like.
他夸大其词地说外面停着一辆 他的小货车 里面装满了孩子
He doubled down on it. Told them he had a load of kids in a van outside.
果然是他的风格
Of course he did.
再敢给我打电话 我就弄死你
You call me again, I'll make sure you breathe your last,
满嘴喷粪的臭婊子
you fucking cow of a cunt!
干得漂亮 问题解决了 我就不该费事来一趟
Well, that's sorted. Great work, Dad. I shouldn't have bothered coming up.
熊宝 她是谁?
Who is she, bear?
是酒吧的一个客人
Uh, she's this woman.
这段时间一直缠着我
She came into the pub, and she's been pestering me for some time.
天哪 你辞职了吗?
Oh my God. Have you quit?
没有 因为辞职意味着认输
No, because that would mean she wins.
这不是输赢的问题 唐尼 事关你的安全呀 快辞职吧
It's not about winning, Donny. It's about your safety. Quit!
在你找到新工作之前 我们会资助你的 对吧 杰瑞?
We will sub you until you find a new job, won't we, Gerry?
我觉得这孩子说得对 这场仗我们不能输
I think the boy's right. It is about winning.
我的天哪
Oh, for goodness' sake.
听着 没事的 好吗?
Look, look, it's fine. Okay?
我已经报过案了 给警察打个电话 请他们来一趟
The police are aware of the situation, so give 'em a call, get 'em down here.
这一切很快就会结束的 我保证
It'll be over soon, all right? I promise.
没事 我来接
It's all right. I'll get it.
是你吗 小驯鹿?
Is that you, reindeer?
驯鹿宝贝
请喝茶
Here's your cup of tea.
谢谢
Thank you.
我了解到这是一桩骚扰案件
I understand this is a harassment case.
是的
That's right.
骚扰你们的人是谁?
And who is the person in question?
一个该死的贱人
She's a fucking bitch, that's who.
杰瑞 要不还是让我们来说吧
Tell you what, Gerry, why don't you let us handle this?
有需要的话我们会叫你
Uh, we'll call you if we need you.
这个女人已经跟踪我有一段时间了
Well, she's this woman, and she's been, like, stalking me for a while.
伦敦那边的警察 警告过她不准再骚扰我
I have this harassment warning out against her,
所以我想 她联系我父母的这个行为
so I assume now that she's contacted my parents,
应该构成骚扰了吧?
she's broken it, right?
严格来说 她没有骚扰你 她骚扰的是你父母
Technically, she's not harassing you. She's harassing your parents.
你在开玩笑吧?
You're kidding me?
如果你们想快刀斩乱麻
If you want a quick resolution,
最好的选择是让你父母 在苏格兰这边另行指控她
your parents would be best off making a separate allegation up here.
但这也太荒谬了
But that's ridiculous.
我知道听起来有些繁琐
I know it can feel convoluted,
但我们会尽力高效地
but, um, you know, we will do our very best to deal with the situation
解决眼下的问题
as, um, as effectively as possible.
不好意思 这笔好像坏了
Sorry, this pen's not working.
喔 瞧呀 原来是这么用的 抱歉
Oh, look. Sorry, there it is.
麻烦的小东西
One of those twisty ones.
那我们就开始吧?
Shall we begin?
我在苏格兰待了一个星期 等候警方采取行动
I spent a week in Scotland, waiting for the police to take action,
眼看着玛莎不停地来电骚扰
watching on as Martha kept calling.
又来找骂了 是吧?
Fucking come back for more, have you?
是 就知道你会这么说 该死的白痴
Aye, you would say that, you fucking imbecile.
见证着这一切对我爸妈造成的危害
Seeing the toll it was taking on my parents.
我爸因为吼叫而嗓音嘶哑
My dad's croaky voice from shouting.
能帮我倒点橙汁吗?
Could you pour me some orange juice?
无论我做什么 我妈都会温情夸赞
My mum forcing this sentiment onto everything I did.
你是个好孩子
You're a good boy.
所以没过多久 我就决定展开自救了
So it wasn't long before I decided to take action myself.
如果警察动作太慢 不能及时保护我们
I figured if the police were too slow to act, too slow to protect us,
那玛莎有可能做出更可怕的事情来
then Martha might do something worse.
是时候反客为主 掌握主动权了
It was time to take matters into my own hands.
玛莎
Martha.
离我的家人远一点
Leave my family alone.
- 我不知道你在说什么 驯鹿宝贝 - 别骚扰我的家人
- I don't know what you're talking about. - Leave my fucking family alone.
不然就永远别想跟我在一起了
If you don't, we will never be together.
明白吗?
Do you understand?
可是你报了警 我以为我们已经没可能了
I thought, with the police, we weren't on the cards anyway.
闭嘴 安静听我说
Shut up. Be quiet for a second.
只要你不再骚扰我的家人...
If you leave my family alone...
我今晚就满足你的需求
I will hang your curtains tonight.
但我想确保准确无误地 满足你的全部需求
I wanna make sure I get it right though. All of it.
所以 给我写封邮件吧
So put it in an email.
告诉我你想对我做什么
What you want to do to me.
想让我怎么满足你
How you want me to... hang them.
但我喜欢粗暴的 好吗?
But I like it rough, okay?
所以内容越变态 越扭曲
So make sure it's as sick, twisted,
越丧心病狂越好 好吗?
as depraved as you can write it, yeah?
好的 小驯鹿
Oh yeah, reindeer.
好了
Okay.
下流的小色鬼 偶要强上你 痛骂你、用尖利勿品捅穿你
别想跑 我会用链子把你栓起来 惩罚你这淘气鬼
iPhone发送
下流的小色鬼 偶要强上你
转发至乔安·卡尔瓦警官
邓恩先生
Now, Mr. Dunn,
本次对话会全程录音
please note this interview is being recorded.
你并未被捕 随时可以自行离开
You are not under arrest, and you are free to leave at any point.
好的 谢谢
Okay. Um, thank you.
你也有权咨询独立法律意见 若你有此意愿的话
You're also entitled to independent legal advice, if you wish.
不 我觉得没那个必要
no, I d... I don't think that's necessary.
既如此 事先申明 我已在问话前 将你的个人法律权利告知
In that case, please know this interview is being held under caution.
慢着 抱歉 现在这是什么情况?
Uh, wait. Sorry, what's going on?
你昨天在街上 跟玛莎·史考特见面了吗?
Did you meet Martha Scott in the street yesterday?
对 碰巧遇到的
Yeah, like, by chance.
你让她给你发送具有威胁性的 性骚扰邮件了吗?
Did you ask her to send you a sexually threatening email?
没有
No.
但我想确保准确无误地...
I wanna make sure I get it right.
满足你的全部需求 所以 给我写封邮件吧
All of it. So put it in an email.
告诉我你想对我做什么 想让我怎么满足你
What you want to do to me. How you want me to... hang them.
从头到尾 玛莎都有录音
Martha had taped everything.
- 我和你去野餐 - 天啊
- I'll picnic with you. - Oh my!
- 我们做过的一切 - 那我就满足你的需求
- Everything. - I'll hang your curtains.
那些关于"挂窗帘"和"满足需求"的隐喻
The curtain references.
我对你是认真的
I'm serious about you.
那次我开玩笑说目光被她吸引
This one time I'd joked about checking her out.
我只是个普通男人呀 玛莎 拜托
Hey, I'm only human, Martha. Come on!
还有那次 我们调侃我阴茎的尺寸
This other time we laughed about my penis size.
- 我简直不敢相信自己的耳朵 - 25厘米哦 25厘米
- I couldn't believe what I was hearing. - Ten inches all round.
我记得这感觉 这种被当场戳穿 时间瞬间凝固
I remember that feeling, that caught red-handed, time-stood-still,
心态爆炸 血冲脑门 几欲发狂的感觉
bomb-in-a-war-zone, hot-fucking-flush madness.
她把一切全录下来了?
She's taped everything?
是不是全部 我无法断言
I can't speak for everything,
但她还给我们看了 一封你求她跟你肛交的邮件
but she also showed us an email from you soliciting for anal sex.
不 那是我一个损友用我邮箱发的
No, that was my fucking friend on my account.
他就是个白痴 发着玩的
He's... he's an idiot. He... he did it for a laugh.
她在骚扰我父母 我这么做只是想阻止她
She's... she's harassing my parents. I just... I just needed it to stop.
我同情你的处境 但也请配合我们警方的工作
I sympathize with your position, but you must allow us to do our job.
某种意义上 你的行为可以被视为诱人犯罪
In a certain light, this could be seen as entrapment.
但史考特女士并不想对你提出指控
But Ms. Scott does not wish to take any action against you.
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
史考特女士并不想对你提出指控
Ms. Scott does not wish to take any action against you.
指控我?
Against me?
什么鬼? 是她在跟踪我啊
What the hell? She's... she's... she's stalking me.
我建议你道歉
I suggest you apologize
以便警方以适当的方式进行工作
and let us go about doing our job again in the correct manner.
道歉? 对她? 你在跟我开玩笑吗?
Apologize? To her? Are you kidding me?
再说了 我要怎么道歉?
I mean, how would I even apologize?
我们可以替你转达歉意
We can pass along your apologies
然后强烈建议她 从今往后跟你各走各路
and then suggest to her, very strongly, that the two of you part ways.
警方不想再听到你们二人有任何纠葛
The police do not want to hear from either of you again.
你把我和她相提并论?
You're putting us on an even playing field?
所以呢?
Well?
跟她说我很抱歉
Tell her I'm sorry.
警察杠杠来过了 哈哈
那傻子说已后不想再官我们的事 让我俩各走各路
哈哈哈 想得美 做梦
对了 窝一直都有录音
从我的iPhone发送
我忽然意识到
It suddenly dawned on me
这一切都是玛莎精心设计好的
that Martha knew exactly what she was doing.
如何在纠缠我的同时 逃避法律的制裁
Exactly how to get to me and still evade the law.
因为她已身经百战了
It's because she's been here countless times before.
她是一名惯犯 经验丰富的老手
She was a repeat offender. A seasoned pro.
我的跟踪狂是个经验丰富的老手
My stalker was a seasoned pro.
你怎么会这么蠢 唐尼? 居然想去陷害她?
How could you be so stupid, Donny? Framing her?
- 你在想什么呀? - 确实很蠢
- What the hell were you thinking? - I know. I know.
那女人袭击了我 唐尼
This woman attacked me, Donny.
现在我无论走到哪里都担心会撞见她
Everywhere I go, I'm worried I might bump into her.
而你却跟我说这辈子都甩不掉她了?
Now you're telling me I'm stuck with that for the rest of my life?
不用你说 我跟你一样苦恼 好吧?
You don't need to tell me. I feel the same way.
万一她找到我的推特页面
What if she finds my Twitter, Donny,
像那晚在酒吧时一样 胡说八道怎么办?
and starts spewing crap like she did in the pub that day?
或许你该暂时关闭社交帐号
Maybe you could take your socials down for a bit.
是吗 这就是你的建议?
Really? That's your suggestion?
至少删掉 所有跟彩虹族群有关的内容吧
Well, at the very least, get rid of all the rainbow unicorn stuff.
明哲保身
You know, protect yourself.
你是认真的吗? 这就是你的建议? 做个缩头乌龟
Are you serious? That's your recommendation? Hide myself.
如果你担心她大放厥词 就别给她抛诱饵
If you're worried about her opinions, don't give her the bait.
诱饵?
Bait?
拜托 泰瑞 我在努力想办法
Come on, Teri. I'm trying here.
在问题解决之前 稍微低调一点有什么不对?
What's wrong with having to lie low for a bit until this is all sorted?
因为那会剥夺我的灵魂
Because of what it takes from me.
你知道我有多不容易才走出来
Do you understand what it's like to get to a place in my life
展现真实的自己吗?
where I can even walk out the door?
现在你让我再走回去 把自己封闭起来 就因为你捅的篓子
And now I need to walk back in and bolt it shut, all because of you.
是因为我 还是因为某个变态在跟踪我?
Because of me or because some fucking psycho is stalking me?
因为你听起来像是 把这一切都怪在我头上了
Because just there it sounded like you were blaming me for all this.
她脑子有毛病 唐尼
She's mentally ill, Donny,
而你放任她胡来
and you indulged her.
拜托 亏你说得出口
Oh, please. Only you could make out
一个暴力跟踪狂正在摧毁我的生活
that having a violent stalker ruining my life
而这竟是我的错?
is somehow my fault.
你真想跟我聊这个话题?
You really wanna go there?
对 我倒真想听听你的高见
Yeah, I actually fucking do.
我认为你乐在其中
I think you love it.
我认为你在生活中 恰恰需要像她那样的人
I think it fits you perfectly having her in your life.
她眼中的你 正是你一心渴望成为的模样
Seeing you as the thing you try so hard to be.
她是你内心阴暗面的化身 是你一直压抑的
She's the embodiment of all your nasty repressions,
邪恶自我的映照
bottled up into one human being.
天啊 泰瑞 拜托
Jesus, Teri, come on.
你不能让她这样影响我们的感情
You can't let her affect us like this.
不是她在影响我们 是你自己
It's not her affecting us. It's you.
我不能再这样下去了
I can't be in this anymore.
我的生活不能这样 没完没了地混乱下去
I can't have this endless disorder in my life.
等一下
Hold on, hold on.
你要跟我分手吗? 就因为她?
Are you breaking up with me because of her?
不 是因为你
No. Because of you.
我知道跟泰瑞的感情结束了
I knew it was over with Teri.
转身离去的那一瞬间 她对我关闭了心门
She shut off her mind towards me the second she turned away.
曲终 人散
Done. Gone.
在跌入低谷的此刻
And now at rock bottom,
我所能找的唯一一丝慰藉
the only positive I could glean from the whole situation
就是情况已经不能变得更糟了
was that it couldn't get any worse from here.
不可能再有比这更糟的局面了
Surely it couldn't get any worse from here.
总有一天偶们会在一起的 小驯鹿 只有你和我
从我的iPhone发送
- 你好 - 你好
- Yes, mate. - Hello.
- 麻烦给我来两杯这里的招牌啤酒 - 好的
- Can I get two pints of house, please? - Yeah, yeah.
不 你不能进来
No, you can't come in here.
- 你不能拦我 - 能 你被酒吧禁入了
- Can't stop me. - You're barred.
狄格西 去把格莱希叫来
Digsy, get Greggsy, will you?
- 他提早下班了 - 为什么?
- He's clocked off early. - Why?
去办点事 他要取货
Air strike, mate. He's picking up.
见鬼 那就去找吉诺
For fuck's sake. Get Gino.
- 也不行 - 为什么?
No can do. - Why?
- 天啊 - 那我就坐在这儿等着吧
- Oh my God. - I guess I'll sit here and wait, then.
不行 休想 我要报警了
No, you won't. I'll call the police.
报吧 看你能跟他们聊成什么样
Do it. See how far that gets you.
我记得他们说过 不想再管我们俩的事了
I heard they're washing their hands of the both of us.
- 打扰一下 我点的... - 请稍等 好吧?
- Excuse me, mate-- - In a minute, pal, all right?
狄格西 请她出去
Digsy, get her out of here.
- 来吧 女士 - 你他妈的别碰我
- Come on, missy. - Don't you fucking touch me!
你没有权利 没有任何权利碰我
You have no right. No right whatsoever.
现在我来月经了
Now, I'm on my period,
想进来喝杯水 这是我的权利
and I've come in for a glass of water, which is my right to do.
你不能否认一个经期女性 喝水的权力 那是违法的
You cannot deny a woman hydration when she's coming on. That is illegal.
随她去吧
Just fucking leave it, all right?
- 您想要点什么 女士?  - 别给她点餐 别理她
- What can I get you, madam? - Don't serve her, you prick. Ignore her.
见鬼 他们从哪儿把你找来的? 天啊
Fuck me. Where did they find you? Jesus.
去把酒水什么的放冰箱去
Go and stock the fridges or something.
- 抱歉... - 对 您要多少来着? 两杯?
I'm sorry... - Yeah. What was it? Two pints?
- 对 - 好的
Yeah. - Okay.
我建议你把那杯子擦干净
I'd wipe that glass clean if I were you.
上面全是阴道酵母菌
Fucking yeast fingers all over your pint.
你真该瞧瞧 他女朋友那风骚样儿 荡妇一个
You should see the woman he's with. His lady friend. Utter skank.
我们这儿都管他叫驼背佬 因为他爱弯着腰在臭水沟里找女人
We call him Hunchy around here 'cause of his gutter taste in women.
他就像那种贪吃松露的猪
He's like one of those hogs,
用他的脏鼻子闻来闻去寻找目标
always sniffling around for truffles with a shitty nose.
松露猪 这是你的新绰号
Truffles! That's your new nickname.
十英镑 劳驾
Tenner, please, mate.
- 谢谢 - 对了 他是个搞笑艺人
- Ta. - He's a comedian, by the way.
不太搞笑的那种
Not a very good one.
- 跟你在电视上看的不一样 - 给我们讲个笑话呗
- Not the kind of stuff you see on TV. - Tell us a joke, mate.
不 他不会讲笑话 他只会用道具
No, he doesn't do jokes, this one. It's more props.
贴着塑胶大眼睛的水壶之类的怪玩意
Googly eyes on kettles. Weird crap.
超级幼稚
Very immature.
- 你可以用谷歌搜索一下 - 搜什么关键词?
- You should Google it. - What do I Google?
- "垃圾 废物谐星" - "垃圾..."
- "Shite, two-bit comedian." - "Shite--"
不 我开玩笑的 但他实至名归
No, I... I'm joking. I'm joking. That's what it should be under.
试试搜索"唐尼·邓恩喜剧"
Try "Donny Dunn comedy."
"唐尼·邓恩喜剧"
"Donny Dunn comedy."
有了 搜到了
Oh yeah. Here it is.
你们喜欢听短笑话吗? 好啊 去看吉米·卡尔的表演吧
Do you like one-liners? Yeah. Check out Jimmy Carr.
- 天哪 老兄 你这是在搞笑吗?  - 我就说吧?
- Jesus, mate. Is that meant to be funny? - I know.
看看这个 好吧? 这边这个 简直是灾难
Watch this one, right? This one here. Lead balloon.
我有个女儿 现在两个月大
I've got a daughter. She's two months old.
我给她取名阿道夫 以此纪念希特勒
Called her Adolf after Adolf Hitler.
开玩笑的啦
I'm joking! I'm joking!
她已经满三个月了
She's three months old.
老兄 你讲笑话时 好像不该照着笔记本念吧?
Mate! I don't think you should be reading your jokes from your notepad, should you?
显然这是他表演的一部分 所谓的"反笑话"
It's part of the act, apparently. It's "anti-comedy," it's called.
- 一点也不好笑 - 可不是嘛
- Well, it's certainly that. - Yeah. That's so true.
我跟你说 老兄
I tell you what, mate.
你再用谷歌搜索些别的吧
Why don't you Google something else?
"连环跟踪狂 精神虐待律师的听障小孩"
"Serial stalker torments barrister's deaf child."
什么玩意 老兄?
What's that?
"连环跟踪狂精神虐待
"Serial stalker torments
律师的听障小孩"
barrister's deaf child."
你毁了我的好心情
You've ruined it!
你这该死的...
You fucking...
Oh fuck.
见鬼
全被你毁了 全毁了
You've ruined it! You fucking ruined it!
- 嘿 冷静 - 你胡说
- Hey, hey, hey, hey! Come on! - Your mouth!
你这张臭嘴
Your fucking mouth!
我警告过你 它会给你惹麻烦的 不是吗?
I warned you it'd get you in trouble, didn't I?
我警告过你
I warned you!
天哪 她怎么忽然发疯了?
Jesus! What the fuck was that about?
我给过她一杯茶
I gave her a cup of tea.
我只是给了她一杯茶而已
写完介封邮件 我再也不想艮你扯上关系
你切底惹毛我了
你介个蠢货丑八怪 干着幼稚的行当
被垃及父母养大 从垃及学校毕业的烂人
我已经对你嘴下刘情了 我从不轻易恨人
但你这次实在太出格子了
或者太出格 反正有那么个说法
你怎么不般回法夫去?
那里全是象你们一家介样的 懒汉、民族主义者、恋童癖和罪犯
干吗来这里?  我们本来很开心 滚远点
我认识的那些大人勿 都很看不惯你
从我的ihpone发送
对了 偶爱你 这点从未改变
从我的iPhone发送
事情是这样的 老弟
That's the thing, son.
你如果报警 酒吧老板会不高兴
If you call the police, the landlord is not gonna like that.
很不高兴
Not at all.
按道理 酒吧里应该一直有管理员盯着
We're supposed to have a manager on at all times.
而我们中途离开的事 不能被上头发现
The fact we just left you there, it's not good, man.
绝对不能
Not good.
也不能被上头发现我们把摄像头转开
They find out we turn the cameras towards the walls
让客人在营业时间结束后继续喝酒
because of the lock-ins,
否则我们可能会因为失职而被炒鱿鱼
and that could be our jobs because that's negligence.
那是失职啊 唐尼
That's negligence, Donny.
要不这么着吧 我们回头去看你的表演 请你喝酒?
Hey, look. How about we come to your gig later and buy you a drink?
咱们好好喝一个
A nice big drink.
我们保证绝不会让她
We'll make sure
再踏进这地方的方圆一公里之内
she doesn't come within a fucking mile of this place ever again.
好吧
Fine.
好
你没事吧 兄弟?
You okay, bro?
- 嘿 你确定没问题吗? - 确定 我没事
- Hey, are you sure you're okay doing this? - Yeah, yeah. I'm fine. I'm fine.
是吗?
Yeah?
那下一个就到你了 伙计
Well, you're up next, dude.
女士们先生们 准备好观看 本轮比赛的压轴好戏了吗?
Ladies and gentlemen, are you ready for your final act of this section?
请保持这样的热情 欢迎唐尼·邓恩登场
Keep that noise going for Donny Dunn!
嘿 好的 谢谢大家 好 好了
Hey! All right! Thank you. Yes! All right.
我们开始吧
All right, here we go.
女士们先生们 我先把这话筒架拿开
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm gonna get this out the way up top.
你们也许看出来了 我的脸上有点淤青和伤痕
You can probably tell my face is a little bruised and battered,
所以我要给大家一个忠告
so here's a piece of advice.
别在车上给人吹箫
Never give the blow job
尤其当你是开车的那一个
if you are the one driving.
好吧 那好
All right, good, good.
只是开场的一个温馨提示
Just a little reminder up top.
本场演出的赞助商是...
This set is brought to you by...
老爹避孕套 优质避孕套
Poppa Condoms. Proper condoms.
套上优质避孕套
Pop a proper condom on.
非常感谢他们赞助这个节目
Thank you very much to them for sponsoring this routine.
好的 笑话时间到
Okay, let's do some jokes.
每次去海滩度假 我都不想戴墨镜
Whenever I go on holiday, uh, I never wanna wear sunglasses on the beach
怕有人会以为我在偷窥他们
in case people think I'm perving on them.
所以 为了打消这种疑虑
So to negate this worry,
我喜欢把眼睛放大
I actually like to widen my eyes.
诸位也有同感吧 这样我看起来就没那么变态了
I think you'll agree, it makes me look less creepy.
好吧 好的 那...
All right. Okay. So...
♪ 这是一只小茶壶 矮矮胖胖 ♪
♪ Here's a little teapot Short and stout ♪
♪ 这是它的把手 ♪
♪ Here is its handle ♪
♪ 这是它的脚 ♪
♪ Here is its gout ♪
不好笑?
No?
好吧 行
All right. Yeah.
不合你们胃口 这笑话 好吧
Not for you, then, that one. Fine.
老爹安全套
Poppa Condoms.
适合爱吃汉堡王的警察朋友们
Proper condoms for policemen who like eating Burger King.
套上优质招牌皇堡警察专用套
Pop a proper Whopper copper condom on.
天哪
Oh boy.
见鬼 真是的...
fucking hell.
你看中的当然不是我的才华 当然不是了
Course you didn't see anything in it. Of course you didn't.
你只是看上了我
You only saw me.
我曾经以为 对...
I used to think, right...
真心以为 听我说 好吧?
Genuinely. Hear me out here, right?
我曾经以为
I used to think
我在这台上带给观众的
that what you're seeing here was, like,
是打破常规的新式幽默
breaking the mold.
我眼看着一个又一个搞笑艺人
You know, I'd watch these fucking other comics
取得我梦寐以求的成功 而我...
rising above me, and I... I just...
我完全想不通 为什么他们可以 我就不行
I never understood why... why them and not me.
可然后 啪
But then, bam!
现实给了我一记响亮的耳光
Reality smacks me in the face.
我太他妈天真了
I am so fucking naive.
我天真地以为自己 拥有独特的搞笑天赋
I was so naive in thinking that this was something special
以至于当一个编剧 假装为我的才华所倾倒
that when a writer sweeps you off your feet
说:"嘿 你很有才华 孩子 我来帮你成为巨星吧"
and says, "Hey, you've got it, kid. Let's make you famous..."
我居然对他说的每一个字深信不疑
you believe every word he's gonna say to you.
因为那是我这辈子都在渴望听到的话
'Cause it's the words you've wanted to hear your entire life.
"我相信你 正如你相信你自己"
"I believe in you... as much as you believe in yourself."
我对他言听计从
And you'll do just about anything in the world he asks of you
因为名望的光环会覆盖所有判断
because... because fame encompasses judgment, right?
我从小到大 一直害怕被人评判
And I... I feared judgment my entire life.
所以我渴望成名 因为一旦出名
That's why I wanted fame, because when you're famous,
在世人眼中 我就是一个名人
people see you as that, famous.
他们不会联想到 那些我害怕被贴上的标签
They're not thinking all the other things that I'm scared they're thinking.
比如"他就是个废物 他很无趣 他是个该死的基佬"之类的
Like, "That guy's a loser or a drip or a fucking faggot."
他们会想 "他是某某节目上的那家伙"
They think, "It's the guy from that thing."
"那家伙很有趣"
"It's the funny guy."
我做梦都想成为一个有趣的人
And I wanted so badly to be the funny guy.
去你妈的红灯 我就快说完了
Fuck your red light. I'm finishing.
所以当那个编剧说
So when this writer says
他只跟离经叛道的人合作 而我呢 为了直面自身的恐惧
he only works with wild ones, and to... to face my own fears, well,
没过多久 我就开始每周末都去他家 吸食成堆的药物
it's not long before I'm round his house, taking boatloads of drugs every weekend.
被诱奸是一件多么神奇的事情呀
And isn't getting groomed magical?
你还没搞清楚状况就被诱奸了
Before you realize you're actually getting groomed.
直到你被迷奸药药倒 躺在他家客厅的沙发上
Until you're passing out from GHB on his living-room couch,
而他用那双恶心的手扯开了你的裤子
while he tears at your trousers with his disgusting hands.
内心深处 你知道他让你做的那些事是错的
And you know it's wrong, deep down, what he's making you do.
但你仍旧不停地回去找他
But you just keep going back.
你会开始问自己
And you start to think,
"我就这么没自尊吗?
"Is my self-respect so fucking low,
我就这么渴望成功吗?
is my lust for success so fucking high,
以至于为了一点虚无缥缈的 成名的希望
that I will repeatedly go back to this man's house
一次又一次地送上门去
and let him abuse me
让他侵犯我?"
for a little peep at fame?"
"你是受害者 不要责怪自己"
"Oh, you're a victim. You mustn't blame yourself."
想法不错 但面对现实吧
Good sentiment, but let's be honest,
当你第四 第五次不省人事 醒来时发现阴茎被他含在嘴里
the fourth or fifth time you've passed out and woken up with your dick in his mouth,
你就该考虑别再回去了
you should probably think about not going back.
但我没有 我还是一往无前
But, no, I just had to keep going.
我非要上赶着去被强奸
I just had to get fucking raped.
想调侃我几句吗 伙计们?
Anything funny to say, boys?
我的自信心低到了极点...
My confidence is so low, right...
你们会喜欢这个后续的
You'll... you'll enjoy this.
...以至于我放任一个疯婆子 走进了我的生活
...that I let this fucking mad bitch into my life.
我在一间酒吧工作 有天我免费给了她一杯茶
I work in a bar, and I gave her this cup of tea on the house.
因为她当时在哭 我想安慰她
She... she was crying, and I wanted to cheer her up.
但她后来一次又一次地找上门
But she... she kept coming back in time and time again,
我明知道她越来越依恋我
and I... I knew she was growing attached,
却依然顺水推舟 只为了满足 我那渴望被关注的愚蠢心态
but I still went along with it to satisfy my own stupid need for attention.
于是我的脸成了这样 这是她干的
Hence the face. She... she did this to me.
瞧瞧
You see...
这就是性侵给人留下的印记
that's what abuse does to you, you know?
它把我变成了...
It made me this...
一块吸引生活中各种怪胎的磁石
sticking plaster for all of life's weirdos. This...
一个血淋淋的伤口 任他们嗅闻
This open wound for them to sniff at.
我知道她是个疯子 我知道她很危险
I knew she was mad, and I knew she was dangerous,
但她夸赞了我 那就足够了
but she flattered me, and that was enough.
而现在...我不知道怎样才能摆脱她
And now... I really don't know where it's gonna end.
这种情况也许会不死不休吧 而我不会杀人
I really think one of us is gonna have to die now, and I'm not a killer.
好啊 走吧 出去吧 下一轮演出会有很多俏皮话听
Yeah, go on, walk out. There'll be puns in the next section.
后台有个打扮成列车长的家伙
There's a guy dressed as a train conductor.
他的演出肯定很有趣
I'm sure that's gonna be funny.
我遇到了一个跨性别女性
I met this trans woman.
你们真该见见她
You should see her.
她是我这辈子见过的最美的人
She's the most beautiful person you've ever met, and
而我就是没办法...
I just couldn't...
我就是没办法
好好爱她
...love her.
我现在明白了
And I see it now.
我明白我为何会为她沦陷
I see what it was that I lost in her.
又为何会以那样的方式将一切搞砸
Moreover, I see why I messed it up in the way that I did.
我知道原因了
And it's because of this, right?
因为在这个世界上 我爱一样东西胜过爱她
It's because I loved one thing in this world more than I did her, right?
一样东西
One thing.
知道它是什么吗?
And do you know what that one thing was?
自我憎恨
Hating myself.
我超爱
I love it.
我上瘾了
I'm addicted to it.
除此之外我什么也不会
I don't know anything else.
因为我不能把握生命中的机会
Because God forbid ever taking a chance at life.
我不能把握得到幸福的机会
God forbid ever taking a chance at happiness.
所以我才搞砸了这段感情
And that's why I messed it up with her.
因为我对自己的痛恨 远胜于对她的爱
Because I hated myself so much more than I loved her.
而我非常 非常爱她
And I loved her so very much.
我这一辈子都在逃避
I've spent my whole life running away.
而这个...
And this...
这场比赛只是我漫长的人生马拉松里 又一段百米跑
This competition, this was just another hundred meters
这场马拉松 我是没法活着完成了
in a marathon I was never gonna finish alive.
所以我现在不想跑了
So I'm gonna stop running now.
因为我已经筋疲力尽 跑不动了
Because I just don't have the legs for it anymore. I just don't.
好吧
Yeah.
老实说 我也不知道 为什么一口气说了这么多
Don't know how I started coming out with all this, to be honest.
真不知道该怎么收尾
Really not sure how to finish.
哦 对了...
Oh, actually...
老爹避孕套 优质避孕套
Poppa condoms, proper condoms
专为在直升机上工作
for policemen working in helicopters
喜欢吃印度菜 和汉堡王的警察朋友量身打造
who enjoy eating Indian food and Burger King.
套上优质招牌皇堡 直升机警察炸薄饼专用避孕套
Pop a proper Whopper chopper copper popadam condom on.
有人想问问题吗?
Are there any questions?
好吧 那么
Well, then,
我很期待赢得这场比赛
I look forward to winning this competition.
根据理查德·加德的话剧 《驯鹿宝贝》改编